musiccritic.com 2018-07-06

# Privacy Policy Music Critic | The Home Of Music Reviews

## Privacy Policy

At Music Critic we respect the privacy of our users and follow a strict privacy policy. This Privacy Policy is applicable to any personal information which we may receive via the web site located at Music Critic, and is devised to help you feel more confident about the privacy and security of your personal details. Be assured that the information you share with Music Critic is kept strictly confidential and fully secure, and that Music Critic will never misuse this information. If you have any questions or concerns about this statement, please contact us at editor@musiccritic.com. 

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for Music Critic.

### Personal User Data

The only ways in which Music Critic may receive personally identifiable information about you is if you knowingly and willingly provide the information by contacting us using email or through one of our service areas, including, but not limited to, contests and promotions. In such areas, the information you disclose is done so knowingly and willingly, at your sole discretion. The personally identifiable information you disclose is optional, and is normally required so as to effectively enter you into any contest we may offer or to reply to your email and correspondence.

If you give us permission to use your email address and name we are not responsible for any correspondence that you may receive. We do not sell or compile lists of email addresses for marketing purposes. Users can opt in to receive our newsletter if they wish. Music Critic will never share the aggregate results of the data it receives with advertisers or any other forms of internet activities. We are committed to user privacy protection and will keep everything secure as stated in the Data Protection Act, 1984.

### Amazon Services

MusicCritic.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com, Amazon.co.uk or Amazon.ca.

### Third Party Sites

Music Critic links to other sites in order to provide you with additional useful information and services. Third party Internet sites and services accessible through Music Critic have separate privacy and data collection practices, independent of us. Music Critic has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies or actions. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. We encourage you to look for and review the privacy policies of any third-party site you visit. 

### Standard User Data

The standard data we collect about our users is not personally identifiable information, meaning it is not information which identifies them as an individual. By using any of Music Critic services or reading its content, you agree that you understand the nature of this data collection.

When you log onto Music Critic, certain standard information is normally collected by our servers. This information may include, but may not be limited to, the location or website from which you came, the time you spend on parts of Music Critic or its related sites, the software you use to browse the Internet (for example Netscape or Microsoft Internet Explorer), the amount of information you access from Music Critic and quantity of pages downloaded. This data collection is standard and common to most websites on the Internet. 

This information does not identify you as an individual, and none of this information will be disclosed in any form that is specific to you as a user of Music Critic, unless otherwise stated. Music Critic will not otherwise knowingly retain and/or disclose this standard data other than in an aggregate forms. 

### Cookies

Parts of Music Critic use cookies to better provide our services and information. On the Internet, a "cookie" is file that a website transfers to a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. This is a common feature of many websites on the Internet, and is employed by Music Critic to better serve to you our services and content. The cookie is stored on your own computer (not our servers) and file that is stored on your computer is small in size and does not identify you personally. 

### Further Policy

It is a Music Critic policy that we will not disclose personally identifiable information you may choose to submit to Music Critic to any third parties. We follow a strict policy of no 'spam' and no sales of personally identifiable information. 

### Children

We welcome users of all ages to our content and services. If you are under the age of thirteen (13), we do, however, specifically request that you have the permission of your parents or legal guardian to view any content at Music Critic and to take part in any and all services we offer, as we cannot and will not be held responsible for any information received or disclosed by our users. 

### Notes to Parents

We respect that you may wish to monitor the content and services your child uses on the Internet. If you wish for your child to be removed from any and/or all Music Critic services, please send an email specifically requesting your wish to editor@musiccritic.com. Please note, however, that while we will subsequently use our best endeavours to prevent your child from using our services, we cannot and will not be held responsible for access to our services your child may subsequently gain, as this is out of our control. 

### User Consent

By using our Web site, you consent to the collection and uses of the information detailed here. Any changes in our Privacy Policy will appear on this page so you are aware of what we collect and how we use it. 

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact editor@musiccritic.com.
